[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community
So at this point I think it's good to basically do
现在我觉得是时候
an overview of the different kinds of visualization that there are.
对不同种类的可视化做一个综述
For example, there's mathematical visualization.
比如 数学可视化
This is the visualization of data generated from a mathematical equation
这是对由数学公式得出的数据进行的可视化
that's readily available just by running a computer program to generate the data.
只要用计算机程序运行并生成数据就可以了
A good example of this is the Mandelbrot set here, this black object.
一个很好的例子是Mandelbrot集 左上角黑色的那个图
This is basically a shape that's in the complex plane,
这个形状是一个复平面上
these are all complex numbers, and
有很多复数
you get this shape basically by starting with zero in the complex plane, zero-zero,
得到这个形状 从零点(0, 0)开始
and you take that and you multiply it times itself and add a constant, and
与自身相乘 再加上一个常数
then multiply that result times itself and add the same constant.
将所得结果再与自身相乘 再加上那个常数
Then keep multiplying it times itself adding a constant.
如此重复将结果与自身相乘 再加上一个常数的过程
Depending on which constant you have corresponds to a point in the complex
根据你选的常数不同 得到的是
plane.
复平面中不同的点
And if you start at zero and keep adding that constant, squaring and
如果你从零点开始重复这个过程
adding that constant.
加常数 求平方 再加常数
If that goes off to infinity, you're out in this purplish region.
如果这样无穷地继续下去 那你会进入这紫色区域
If that sticks around, you're in the black region.
如果数字徘徊不前 你会在黑色区域
Now mathematicians knew that these dynamics were interesting
数学家早在二十世纪初就知道
in the early 1900s, but
这个动态过程是很有趣的
they did know how interesting the dynamics were or what was going on.
但那时还不知道究竟多有趣 也不知道究竟是这么回事
And it wasn't until plotted this.
直到这个图被绘制出来
Using data visualization to plot the results of these points,
使用数据可视化来绘制计算结果的这些点
to find that the dynamics were very interesting.
从而了解其动态性的确非常有趣
You got all this great structure.
你得到了这个很棒的结构
You could zoom into a little section here, and see even more, and more detail, and
即使放大到很小的区域 你还能看到更多更多的细节
that was something we just hadn't encountered before in mathematics, and
这是以前在数学上从未遇到过的
so visualization kind of revolutionized this area of mathematics in our
可以说是可视化带来了数学的这个领域的革命
understanding of this area of mathematics by basically getting the data
通过把数据从数学公式里提取出来
out of this mathematical equation and through our visual
并利用视觉感知来进行认知
perception into a cognitive process so we could better understand it.
这样我们有更好的理解
So, if If you pick a point inside this and
如果你在这里面选一个点
you start to look at the dynamics, you get what's called a Julia set.
开始观察这个动态 你就得到了一个Julia集
And this plotted in the complex plane.
同样也是绘制在复平面上
And one of the things I worked on with this
我做过的工作之一
was to take this complex Julia set and look what's going on in the quaternions.
就是利用这个复Julia集 研究四元数
And again, data visualization is really helpful because you get
数据可视化再次非常有用
these whorl patterns.
因为你得到这个螺纹图案
That are basically connecting different parts of this Julia set to other parts of
基本上来说 这个图案 把朱利亚集的不同部分
this Julia set through these additional dimensions, and
通过额外的维度连接起来
you couldn't understand that very well without actually being able to visualize
如果不实际可视化出来 你不会明白
how those connections are being made.
这些连接是如何建立的
There's also scientific visualization.
除此之外，还有科学可视化
And this is the visualization of scientific data.
即对科学数据进行的可视化
And that data tends to either be measured from real world scientific devices or it.
这里的数据要么是通过科学仪器 在现实世界上测量得到的
Comes as the result of a lengthy expensive supercomputer simulation.
要么是用昂贵的超级计算机 进行仿真得到的结果
In here visualization can be really useful because if you have supercomputer
可视化在这里是非常有用的 因为如果你有超级计算机进行仿真
simulation, you can use the visualization as the simulation is being generated
你可以在仿真的过程中使用可视化
to determine if there's problems with the simulation or
来观察其中是否存在问题
if you want to steer the simulation in a more productive direction.
你也可以控制仿真使其更有成效
This tends to be coordinate data, spatial coordinates, XYZ coordinates, time.
科学可视化的数据往往是 空间坐标数据（XYZ）和时间
It measures things like temperature and pressure and other physical quantities,
还包括温度 压力和其他一些物理量
and this is an example from my own work where we're visualizing sort of the fronts
图中是一个我自己研究工作的例子
of the blood flow as it's coming through
显示血液的锋面流向
a lower aorta that happens to be has an aneurysm here.
这里下主动脉处碰巧有个动脉瘤
It's bulging.
它在膨胀
And the actual calculation of these fronts requires a tremendous amount of
实际计算这些锋面需要巨大的
computer time.
计算量
Work in this area has recently taken as long as a month to compute these fronts.
最近的工作中 用了长达一个月 来计算这些锋面
But we're able to visualize it very quickly and interactively so
但是我们可以将其可视化 快捷 可交互
we can see what's going on to better understand the complicated nature
使得我们可以看到究竟在发生什么 来更好的理解这个由数百万次仿真
of this flow which is resulting from millions of simulation steps.
所得到的血流过程的复杂本质
And finally there's information visualization.
最后一类 是信息可视化
This is the visualization of more abstract, non-coordinate data.
即对更抽象的 没有坐标的数据 进行的可视化
For example, what we'll look at in our Data Visualization Course will be,
举例来说 我们将在这门课上看到
for example, relationship data.
关系数据
And this happens to be a visualization that my students and
图中是我和我学生前几年搞的可视化
I worked on a few years ago, these are basically connections between different
它显示了不同的Flicker用户之间
flicker users on the flicker photo sharing website.
在Flicker网站上分享照片的关系连接
And there's 7 million of these connections and so
一共有7百万这样的连接
it's far to many to be able to understand by looking at just an ordinary.
这对于普通的图来说 实在是太多了
Graph, but by coloring and clustering and laying things out,
通过图形 并添加颜色 聚集成群 合理摆放 等
we can start to see certain people are more popular and certain
我们可以开始看出 某些人更受欢迎
photo collections are gaining more attention and we can provide
某些相册获得了更多关注
an overview of all of t hat data that you can then investigate in more detail.
我们可以提供所有数据的一个概观 以便于研究更多的细节
And so it relies more heavily on this information visualization.
这很大程度上更依赖于 信息可视化
It relies more heavily on the ability to process the data
很大程度上依赖于 将抽象数据
from its abstract form into something geometric, something concrete that we
处理为几何学意义上的数据 的能力
can then transmit to our brain from our visual channels.
将数据转化为具体的图形 可以通过视觉通道传输给头脑
But that conversion becomes more challenging with information
但是这种转化对于信息可视化来说
visualization, then perhaps it is with scientific or mathematical visualization.
比对于科学可视化和数学可视化 都要更困难
And there's a variety of different domains that visualization is used in.
可视化被用于各种不同的领域
It's used in medical imaging.
它被用于医学成像
For example taking CT Scans and
比如 把CT扫描图
being able to reconstruct three dimensional shapes from that so
重现为三维形状
you can get a better context of where you are spaciouly and the patient data.
这样你能更好地看到病理位置 及病人的数据信息
Being able to take business intelligence information marketing results and being
还可以把商业情报信息 市场营销结果
able to present those in a way that makes it easier to make a business decision.
以一种更容易做出商业决策 的方式呈现出来
Educational visualization, this is a visualization of how quaternions multiply,
此外还有教育可视化 这是我几年前
that I made a few years ago
制作的四元数乘法的可视化
that helps the user understand geometrically what's
来帮助用户从几何上搞明白 这抽象的四维数字系统
going on with an otherwise abstract four dimensional number system.
究竟是怎么一回事
Or geographic information systems, taking data that's geographic in nature,
又如地理信息系统 获取本质上算是地理学的数据
and being able to plot that in ways that helps you reason
将其以各种方式绘制出来 以帮助你合理的推断你所在区域
about your region, or about the world as a whole.
或者整个世界
And finally, there's some modes of visualization, and
最后 可视化分为不同模式
these are important to understand for data visualization in general.
这对整体上理解数据可视化 是很重要的
There's three that we'll go over., the first is interactive visualization and
我们会谈三种模式 第一种是交互式可视化
this is the kind of visualization that's used for discovery.
这类可视化被用于探索和发现
Basically, a single investigator would use this.
基本上来说 单干的研究者 会使用交互式可视化
Maybe one or two collaborators might join in, but
也许会有一到两个合作者加入
its basically a single investigator in front of a computer.
但基本上是单干的研究者 坐在计算机前
And, plotting data to try to understand what's going on with the data.
绘制数据 以试图理解 这数据究竟意味着什么
You've got full control of the data and you can change what data sets and
你对数据有完全的控制 你能 实时地改变显示哪些数据集
how it's displayed on the fly in order to help understand what you're looking at.
或是改变它们的显示方式 来帮助理解你眼前的数据
And that's different than, for example, presentation visualization.
与之不同的 是呈现式可视化
Presentation visualization is the kind of visualization that we use for
呈现式可视化属于那种
communication.
我们用于交流的可视化
Its a kind of visualization that you would see in a video or
这类可视化是你在视频
in a slide presentation and its intended for a large group or
或者幻灯片演示中所看到的 其目的是为了
mass audience to basically communicate some aspect of data to that mass audience.
将数据的某些方面 传达给大量的观众
And the difference between presentation visualization and
呈现式可视化与交互式可视化
interactive visualization,
不同之处主要在于
mainly, is that presentation visualization doesn't support user input.
呈现式可视化不支持用户输入
So you're just sitting there and
你只能坐在那里观察
observing, but you can't really interact with the data.
但不能与数据交互
You're just sort of getting
你所得到的数据已经打包好
the data packaged in a way that helps you understand it, without the interaction.
可以帮助你理解但无法交互
In between here, there's the Internet has basically enabled this third mode of
在这两种模式之间 互联网带来了第三种模式
visualization that has been called interactive storytelling.
被称为交互式讲故事
And these are presentation visualizations, but
它们属于演示可视化
they are presented via interactive web pages.
其以可交互的网页形式呈现
And so they allow the viewer to interact with the data in some limited fashions.
允许用户以有限的方式 与数据进行交互
The viewer can't change the dataset.
观看者不能修改数据集
But they can sort of investigate a little bit further and
但能对数据更进一步地调查
there's more information that can be presented all at once,
更多信息能一次性呈现出来
as it would be with a presentation visualization.
就像呈现式可视化一样
And so another way of describing these differences is to visualize
另一种描述这些不同点的方式 是将不同模式
the modes of visualization, and so I've laid them out in a table.
可视化出来 因此我做了个表格
We can compare them in terms of user interaction.
我们可以按照用户交互 来比较它们
Interactive visualization,
在交互式可视化中
the user controls everything including what data set you're looking at.
用户拥有完全控制 包括想看什么数据集
In presentation visualization the user is only observing, there is no interaction.
在呈现式可视化中 用户只观察不交互
In interactive storytelling there's a presentation, but
在互动式讲故事中 有呈现式的部分
the user can still filter the data, or inspect details of the data, but
但用户仍能过滤数据 或检视数据细节等
can't necessarily change the data set that they're looking at.
但用户不能改变 他们观察的数据集
There's different graphics rendering methods.
图形显示方式也有不同
You would use real-time rendering.
你会用到实时显示
Anytime you're supporting interaction as you make changes, your
任何时候为支持修改过程中的互动
display needs to respond to those changes so you need real time graphics to do that.
你的显示器需要响应你的修改 所以你需要实时图形来实现
Where as presentation visualization, the rendering is precomputed and stores,
而呈现式可视化 渲染被预先计算好
say on video or images in a slide show.
并存储在视频或者幻灯片里
The target audiences are different.
目标观众也不一样
For presentation visualization, you're targeting a mass audience,
呈现式可视化的是针对于大量观众的
your colleagues or everybody that goes to your webpage, whereas the target for
如你的同事或任何 访问你网页的人
interactive visualization is an individual investigator or maybe a small group of.
而交互式可视化的目标 是单一研究者
Collaborators that are working on understanding some data.
或一小组试图理解数据 的合作者
And finally, the medium is different.
最后 媒介也是不同的
When you're running interactive visualization,
当你运行交互式可视化时
you're running software and the Internet can enable some software to be run, but
你在运行软件 虽然互联网也可用于运行软件
it's basically running a software program on a computer.
但基本上是在 计算机上运行软件
In order to display the data.
为了显示数据
When you're doing interactive storytelling, you're working mostly on
当你交互性讲故事时
the Internet or some other information kiosk that can support a mass audience.
通常是在互联网上 或支持大量观众的信息亭
When you're working on presentation visualization,
从事呈现式可视化工作时
you're working on slide shows, or video, or some other format that
你先把视觉呈现 用 幻灯片 视频 或 其他格式
allows you to prerecord the visuals, and then present them to a mass audience.
预先记录好 然后呈现给大量观众
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community